let questions = {
  /* ---------------------------HTML Questions------------------------- */
  Html: [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: " The correct sequence of HTML tags for starting a webpage is -",
    answer: "HTML, Head, Title, Body",
    options: [
      "Head, Title, HTML, body",
      "HTML, Body, Title, Head",
      "Head, HTML, Title, Body",
      "HTML, Head, Title, Body"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " Which of the following element is responsible for making the text bold in HTML?",
    answer: "b",
    options: [
      "pre",
      "a",
      "b",
      "br"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following tag is used for inserting the largest heading in HTML?",
    answer: "h1",
    options: [
      "h4",
      "h2",
      "h1",
      "h6"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "How to create an unordered list (a list with the list items in bullets) in HTML?",
    answer: "ul",
    options: [
      "ol",
      "ul",
      "li",
      "i"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following tag is used to insert a line-break in HTML?",
    answer: "br",
    options: [
      "a",
      "pre",
      "br",
      "b"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Where is the meta tag only found?",
    answer: "The home page",
    options: [
      "The last page",
      "The home page",
      "The second page",
      "The third page"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What should values always be enclosed in?",
    answer: "Quotation marks",
    options: [
      "Quotation marks",
      "Commas",
      "Parenthesis",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },



   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "The <hr> tag in HTML is used for",
    answer: "horizontal ruler",
    options: [
      "new line",
      "vertical ruler",
      "new paragraph",
      "horizontal ruler"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following tag is used to make the underlined text?",
    answer: "u",
    options: [
      "i",
      "ul",
      "u",
      "pre"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the following HTML tag is the special formatting tag?",
    answer: "pre",
    options: [
      "p",
      "pre",
      "b",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------CSS Questions------------------------- */
Css:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The property in CSS used to change the background color of an element is - ",
    answer: "background-color",
    options: [
      "bgcolor",
      "color",
      "background-color",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The HTML attribute used to define the inline styles is - ",
    answer: "style",
    options: [
      "style",
      "styles",
      "class",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following CSS property is used to set the background image of an element?",
    answer: "background-image",
    options: [
      "background-attachment",
      "background-image",
      "background-color",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct syntax to make the background-color of all paragraph elements to yellow?",
    answer: "p {background-color : yellow;}",
    options: [
      "p {background-color : yellow;}",
      "p {background-color : #yellow;}",
      "all {background-color : yellow;}",
      "all p {background-color : #yellow;}"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following property is used as the shorthand property of margin properties?",
    answer: "margin",
    options: [
      "margin-right",
      "margin-left",
      "margin",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "The CSS property used to specify the transparency of an element is -",
    answer: "opacity",
    options: [
      "filter",
      "opacity",
      "visibility",
      "overlay"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following is used to specify the subscript of text using CSS?",
    answer: "vertical-align: sub",
    options: [
      "vertical-align: sub",
      "vertical-align: super",
      "vertical-align: subscript",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "The CSS property used to specify whether the text is written in the horizontal or vertical direction?",
    answer: "writing-mode",
    options: [
      "writing mode",
      "text-indent",
      "word-break",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following syntax is correct in CSS to make each word of a sentence start with a capital letter?",
    answer: "text-transform: capitalize;",
    options: [
      "text-style: capital;",
      "transform: capitalize;",
      "text-transform: capital;",
      "text-transform: capitalize;"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The CSS property used to make the rounded borders, or rounded corners around an element is -",
    answer: "border-radius",
    options: [
      "border-collapse",
      "border-radius",
      "border-spacing",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------JavaScript Questions------------------------- */
Javascript:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which type of JavaScript language is ___",
    answer: "Object-based",
    options: [
      "Object-Oriented",
      "Object-based",
      "Assembly-language",
      "High-level"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " Which one of the following also known as Conditional Expression:",
    answer: "immediate if",
    options: [
      "Alternative to if-else",
      "Switch statement",
      "If-then-else statement",
      "immediate if"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In JavaScript, what is a block of statement?",
    answer: "block that combines a number of statements into a single compound statement",
    options: [
      "Conditional block",
      "block that combines a number of statements into a single compound statement",
      "both conditional block and a single statement",
      "block that contains a single statement"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "The 'function' and 'var' are known as:",
    answer: "Declaration statement",
    options: [
      "Keywords",
      "Data Types",
      "Declaration statements",
      "Prototypes"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following variables takes precedence over the others if the names are the same?",
    answer: "The local element",
    options: [
      "Global Variable",
      "The local element",
      "The two of the above",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which one of the following is the correct way for calling the JavaScript code?",
    answer: "Function/Method",
    options: [
      "Preprocessor",
      "RMI",
      "Function/Method",
      "Triggering Event"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "In the JavaScript, which one of the following is not considered as an error:",
    answer: "Division by zero",
    options: [
      "Syntax error",
      "Missing of semicolons",
      "Division by zero",
      "Missing of Bracket"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Choose the correct snippet from the following to check if the variable 'a' is not equal the 'NULL':",
    answer: "if(a!==null)",
    options: [
      "if(a!=null)",
      "if(a!null)",
      "if(a!==null)",
      "if(a!)"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "In JavaScript, what will be used for calling the function definition expression:",
    answer: "Function literal",
    options: [
      "Function prototype",
      "Function literal",
      "Function calling",
      "Function declaration"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which one of the following operator is used to check weather a specific property exists or not:",
    answer: "in",
    options: [
      "Exists",
      "exist",
      "within",
      "in"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Node.js Questions------------------------- */
Nodejs:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following statement is correct?",
    answer: "js is Server Side Language",
    options: [
      "js is Server Side Language",
      "js is the Client Side Language",
      "js is both Server Side and Client Side Language",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " What does the REPL stand for?",
    answer: "REPL stands for Read Eval Print Loop.",
    options: [
      "REPL stands for Read Earn Point Learn.",
      "REPL stands for Research Eval Program Learn.",
      "REPL stands for Read Eval Print Loop.",
      "REPL stands for Read Eval Point Loop."
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In which language is Node.js written?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "JavaScript",
      "C",
      "C++",
      "CoffeeScript",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following command is used to install the Node.js express module?",
    answer: "$ npm install express",
    options: [
      "$ npm install express",
      "$ node install express",
      "$ install express",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following variables takes precedence over the others if the names are the same?",
    answer: "The local element",
    options: [
      "Global Variable",
      "The local element",
      "The two of the above",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following extension is used to save the Node.js files?",
    answer: ".js",
    options: [
      ".java",
      ".node",
      ".js",
      ".txt"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The Node.js modules can be exposed using:",
    answer: "exports",
    options: [
      "module",
      "exports",
      "expose",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following module is not a built-in node module?",
    answer: "fsread",
    options: [
      "zlib",
      "https",
      "dgram",
      "fsread"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "In JavaScript, what will be used for calling the function definition expression:",
    answer: "Function literal",
    options: [
      "Function prototype",
      "Function literal",
      "Function calling",
      "Function declaration"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What is the default scope in the Node.js application?",
    answer: "Local",
    options: [
      "Local to object",
      "Global Function",
      "Local",
      "Global"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Express.js Questions------------------------- */
// Expressjs:[

// ],
// /* ---------------------------Angular.js Questions------------------------- */
// Angularjs:[

// ],
/* ---------------------------React.js Questions------------------------- */
Reactjs:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct name of React.js?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "React",
      "React.js",
      "ReactJS",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which of the following are the advantages of React.js?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "React.js can increase the application's performance with Virtual DOM.",
      "React.js is easy to integrate with other frameworks such as Angular, BackboneJS since it is only a view library.",
      "React.js can render both on client and server side.",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following is not a disadvantage of React.js?",
    answer: "The JSX in React.js makes code easy to read and write.",
    options: [
      "React.js has only a view layer. We have put your code for Ajax requests, events and so on.",
      "The library of React.js is pretty large.",
      "The JSX in React.js makes code easy to read and write.",
      "The learning curve can be steep in React.js."
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following command is used to install create-react-app?",
    answer: "npm install -g create-react-app",
    options: [
      "npm install -g create-react-app",
      "npm install create-react-app",
      "npm install -f create-react-app",
      "install -g create-react-app"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
    answer: "Virtual DOM",
    options: [
      "Original DOM",
      "Virtual DOM",
      "Both A and B.",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, which keyword do we use?",
    answer: "Class",
    options: [
      "Constructor",
      "Class",
      "Object",
      "DataObject"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following acts as the input of a class-based component?",
    answer: "Props",
    options: [
      "Class",
      "Factory",
      "Render",
      "Props"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following keyword is used to create a class inheritance?",
    answer: "Extends",
    options: [
      "Create",
      "Inherits",
      "Extends",
      "This"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What is the default port where webpack-server runs?",
    answer: "8080",
    options: [
      "3000",
      "8080",
      "3030",
      "6060"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "How many numbers of elements a valid react component can return?",
    answer: "1",
    options: [
      "1",
      "2",
      "4",
      "5"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Django Questions------------------------- */
// Django:[

// ],
// /* ---------------------------MySQl Questions------------------------- */
// Mysql:[

// ],
/* ---------------------------php Questions------------------------- */
Php:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "PHP stands for - ",
    answer: "Hypertext Preprocessor",
    options: [
      "Hypertext Preprocessor",
      "Pretext Hypertext Preprocessor",
      "Personal Home Processor",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Variable name in PHP starts with - ",
    answer: "$ (Dollar)",
    options: [
      "! (Exclamation)",
      "$ (Dollar)",
      "& (Ampersand)",
      "# (Hash)"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following is the default file extension of PHP?",
    answer: ".php",
    options: [
      ".php",
      ".hphp",
      ".xml",
      ".html"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following is not a variable scope in PHP?",
    answer: "Extern",
    options: [
      "Global",
      "Static",
      "Local",
      "Extern"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following is used to display the output in PHP?",
    answer: "Both echo and print",
    options: [
      "echo",
      "write",
      "print",
      "Both echo and print"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following is the use of strlen() function in PHP?",
    answer: "The strlen() function returns the length of string",
    options: [
      "The strlen() function returns the type of string",
      "The strlen() function returns the length of string",
      "The strlen() function returns the value of string",
      "The strlen() function returns both value and type of string"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following is used for concatenation in PHP?",
    answer: ". (dot)",
    options: [
      "+ (plus)",
      "* (Asterisk)",
      ". (dot)",
      "append()"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following is the use of strpos() function in PHP?",
    answer: "The strpos() function is used to search for a character/text in a string",
    options: [
      "The strpos() function is used to search for the spaces in a string",
      "The strpos() function is used to search for a number in a string",
      "The strpos() function is used to search for a character/text in a string",
      "The strpos() function is used to search for a capitalize character in a string"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct way to create a function in PHP?",
    answer: "function myFunction()",
    options: [
      "Create myFunction()",
      "New_function myFunction()",
      "function myFunction()",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct use of the strcmp() function in PHP?",
    answer: "The strcmp() function is used to compare the strings including case",
    options: [
      "The strcmp() function is used to compare the strings excluding case",
      "The strcmp() function is used to compare the uppercase strings",
      "The strcmp() function is used to compare the lowercase strings",
      "The strcmp() function is used to compare the strings including case"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Mongodb Questions------------------------- */
Mongodb:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "MongoDB is written in ___",
    answer: "All",
    options: [
      "Go",
      "JavaScript",
      "Python",
      "All"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "A collection and a document in MongoDB is equivalent to _________ concepts respectively.",
    answer: "ITable and Row",
    options: [
      "Table and Column",
      "Table and Row",
      "Column and Row",
      "Database and Table"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "in how much time the MongDB writes are written to the journal?",
    answer: "100 ms",
    options: [
      "100 s",
      "60 s",
      "1 s",
      "100 ms"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "In which format MongoDB represents document structure?",
    answer: "BSON",
    options: [
      "BSON",
      ".txt",
      ".Docx",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "A collection in MongoDB is a group of",
    answer: "Related documents",
    options: [
      "Databases",
      "Schema",
      "Rows",
      "Related documents"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "which field is always the first field in the document.?",
    answer: "_id",
    options: [
      "_id",
      "Ob_id",
      "id",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "mongoDB supports",
    answer: "NoSQL",
    options: [
      "RDBMS",
      "NoSQl",
      "Both",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "MongoDB is a ..... type database?",
    answer: "document",
    options: [
      "Relational",
      "objects",
      "document",
      "All"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which statements is correct about mongoose in MongoDB ?",
    answer: "It is used for modeling your application data in node.js",
    options: [
      "It is Java library to connect with MongoDB",
      "It is used for modeling your application data in node.js",
      "It is Python library to connect with MongoDB",
      "It is a PHP library to connect with MongoDB"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The concatenation of the collection name and database name is called a -",
    answer: "Namespace",
    options: [
      "Namespace",
      "MongoDB",
      "sharding",
      "replica"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Springboot Questions------------------------- */
Springboot:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which type of JavaScript language is ___",
    answer: "Object-based",
    options: [
      "Object-Oriented",
      "Object-based",
      "Assembly-language",
      "High-level"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " Which one of the following also known as Conditional Expression:",
    answer: "immediate if",
    options: [
      "Alternative to if-else",
      "Switch statement",
      "If-then-else statement",
      "immediate if"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In JavaScript, what is a block of statement?",
    answer: "block that combines a number of statements into a single compound statement",
    options: [
      "Conditional block",
      "block that combines a number of statements into a single compound statement",
      "both conditional block and a single statement",
      "block that contains a single statement"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "",
    answer: "Declaration statement",
    options: [
      "Keywords",
      "Data Types",
      "Declaration statements",
      "Prototypes"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following variables takes precedence over the others if the names are the same?",
    answer: "The local element",
    options: [
      "Global Variable",
      "The local element",
      "The two of the above",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which one of the following is the correct way for calling the JavaScript code?",
    answer: "Function/Method",
    options: [
      "Preprocessor",
      "RMI",
      "Function/Method",
      "Triggering Event"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "In the JavaScript, which one of the following is not considered as an error:",
    answer: "Division by zero",
    options: [
      "Syntax error",
      "Missing of semicolons",
      "Division by zero",
      "Missing of Bracket"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "",
    answer: "if(a!==null)",
    options: [
      "if(a!=null)",
      "if(a!null)",
      "if(a!==null)",
      "if(a!)"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "In JavaScript, what will be used for calling the function definition expression:",
    answer: "Function literal",
    options: [
      "Function prototype",
      "Function literal",
      "Function calling",
      "Function declaration"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which one of the following operator is used to check weather a specific property exists or not:",
    answer: "in",
    options: [
      "Exists",
      "exist",
      "within",
      "in"
    ]
  },
],


};
